Finding Aid for George R. Larue papers, 1910-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George R. Larue papers 1910-1951
Larue, George R. (George Roger), b. 1882.
4 linear feet
851656 Aa 2
Professor of zoology at University of Michigan. Correspondence, mostly of a professional nature, with students and scholars in the field of zoology; also manuscripts, addresses, lecture notes, and other papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Professor Larue (donor no. 2844 )
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
George R. Larue was born in Paullina, Iowa on January 1, 1882. He received his Ph.D. from the University of Illinois in zoology. Prior to that time, Larue had worked as an assistant biologist at Doane College, 1904-1907, a research technician at the University of Nebraska Medical College, 1907-1909, a research assistant in zoology at the University of Illinois, 1909-1911. He came to the University of Michigan as an instructor in zoology. He became a full professor in 1927 and served as chairman of the department from 1934 to 1949. In addition, Professor La Rue was director of the Biological Station, 1916-1939. He died in 1967.
The Larue papers consists of professor correspondence, 1910 to 1951 and a few of the lecture that he came about the work of the Biological Station and his expertise in the area of parasitology.
Subjects:
Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Zoology.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Zoology.; Larue, George R. (George Roger), b. 1882.
Contributors:
Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Michigan. Dept. of Conservation.; Michigan. Dept. of Health.; Michigan. Stream Control Commission.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vestal, Albert Henry, 1875-1932.
Genre Terms:
genre
- Correspondence
  - 1910-June 1928, 33 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1928-August 1935, 33 folders (Box 2)
    (include letter from Arthur H. Vandenberg, January 5, 1930, regarding national conservation policies; also letter from Albert H. Vestal, January 14, 1931 concerning the Federal Conservation Bill)
  - September 1935-December 1941, 30 folders (Box 3)
    (include letter from Earl C. Michener, March 23, 1936)
  - January 1942-May 1951, 27 folders (Box 4)
- Lectures and other materials
  - Lecture concerning the Biological Station of the University of Michigan, 1920 (Box 4)
  - Lecture concerning sanitation and human parasites, 1921 (Box 4)
  - Lecture concerning parasitology, 1921 (Box 4)
  - Lecture concerning the hundredth anniversary of the birth of Ernst Haeckel, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning course in zoology taught by Drs., La Rue, Hubbs, Ruthven and Shull, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning course in zoology taught by Drs. La Rue, Reighard and Shull, 1915-1916 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning The Principles of Animal Biology by Drs. La Rue, Ruthven and Shull, undated (Box 4)